<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>framework on Sage CS Research</title>
    <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/tags/framework/</link>
    <description>Recent content in framework on Sage CS Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sage-csr.vercel.app/tags/framework/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/frameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/frameworks/</guid>
      <description>What is it? Select a framework Chosing the right framework is a challange. Let&amp;rsquo;s investigate some advantages and desadvantages of each option. We will dive deep into each framework later. First you need to knoe no framewok will save you from hard work. Here is the order given by AI.&#xA;1. Next.js (React-based framework):&#xA;Pros: Excellent for SEO (Search Engine Optimization) due to server-side rendering, good for static content and dynamic routes, large community and ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is NextJS?</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/next/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/next/</guid>
      <description>Key Concepts, Review: Routing: Routing defines how URLs map to specific content or components in your website. Imagine a switchboard that directs users to different departments based on their request. Data Fetching: This involves retrieving data from external sources like APIs or databases to populate your website&amp;rsquo;s content. Think of it as going out to gather information to display on your storefront. Rendering Strategies: There are two main approaches to rendering content in web applications: Client-side Rendering (CSR): All rendering happens in the user&amp;rsquo;s browser after the initial page load.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is React?</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/react/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/react/</guid>
      <description>Fundamentals So You&amp;rsquo;re a JavaScript Developer New to Frameworks? Buckle Up for React!&#xA;As a seasoned JavaScript developer, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely wrestled with DOM manipulation, state management, and the ever-growing complexity of modern web applications. But what if there was a better way? Enter React, the JavaScript library that&amp;rsquo;s taken the front-end world by storm.&#xA;How react works?&#xA;Imagine building Legos. Each Lego brick is a self-contained piece with its own functionality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is NuxtJS?</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/nuxt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/nuxt/</guid>
      <description>Nuxt.js is a free and open-source framework built on top of Vue.js that simplifies building web applications. It&amp;rsquo;s designed to be intuitive and efficient, allowing you to create performant and production-ready web experiences.&#xA;Key Features Here are some key features of Nuxt.js:&#xA;Server-side rendering (SSR): Nuxt.js can pre-render your application on the server, which improves SEO and initial load times. Static site generation (SSG): You can also use Nuxt.js to generate static HTML files, which is ideal for content-heavy websites.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is SvelteJS?</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/svelte/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/svelte/</guid>
      <description>SvelteJS, often referred to as just Svelte, is a relatively new (first released in 2016) but popular front-end development framework. Here are some key things to know about SvelteJS:&#xA;Svelte Key Goals Focus on Performance: Svelte takes a different approach than many other frameworks by compiling code during the build process. This means that the browser doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to do as much work when loading your application, resulting in faster performance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Angular?</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/angular/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/angular/</guid>
      <description>Angular is a popular framework for building single-page web applications (SPAs). It&amp;rsquo;s open-source and backed by Google, making it a reliable choice for web development. Here&amp;rsquo;s a breakdown of what Angular offers:&#xA;Component-based architecture: Angular applications are built using reusable components, which makes your code more organized and easier to maintain. These components define how a specific part of your application looks and behaves. TypeScript: Angular uses TypeScript, a superset of JavaScript, which adds features like static typing for better code maintainability and fewer errors.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
