<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>basics on Sage CS Research</title>
    <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/tags/basics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in basics on Sage CS Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sage-csr.vercel.app/tags/basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Architecture</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/basics/architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/basics/architecture/</guid>
      <description>Software Architecture is not as physical as building architecture, it&amp;rsquo;s equally important for creating well-structured and functional applications. Here are some basic software architecture concepts to get you started:&#xA;Components and Modules: Imagine building blocks. Software is broken down into smaller, independent pieces called components or modules. Each module has a specific function and interacts with others in defined ways.&#xA;Modularity: This principle emphasizes the importance of breaking down complex systems into smaller, manageable modules.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programming</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/basics/programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/basics/programming/</guid>
      <description>In this article we investigate several programming languages. We will understand the difference between them and we will try to explain why we have so many programming languages. Our favorite programming language is Julia. We will explain why and we will try to motivate you to learn multiple programming languages. We think a software engineer should know at least 3 programming languages.&#xA;What is a Programming Language? Here&amp;rsquo;s an explanation of programming languages, interpreters, and compilers:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Symbols</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/basics/symbols/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/basics/symbols/</guid>
      <description>Pictograms, alphabets and numeric symbols are 3 important pillars of civilization.These three, have played a crucial role in the development and advancement of human civilization. Each pillar has had a profound impact on how we communicate, record information, and organize knowledge.&#xA;Pictograms: The earliest form of written communication, pictograms served as a way to visually represent objects, ideas, and events. They laid the foundation for the development of writing systems by establishing the principle of using symbols to convey meaning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expressions</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/basics/expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/basics/expressions/</guid>
      <description>Understanding expressions is fundamental to both computer science and programming. They&amp;rsquo;re the building blocks of code, allowing you to manipulate data, control program flow, and make decisions.&#xA;There are many types of expressions, each serving a specific purpose. Here are some of the most common ones:&#xA;1. Arithmetic Expressions: These expressions perform mathematical operations on numbers, like addition, subtraction, multiplication, and division. You might use them to calculate distances, areas, or any other numerical value needed in your program.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Objects</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/basics/objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/basics/objects/</guid>
      <description>Here is an explanation of object-oriented programming (OOP) paradigm and principles, its advantages and disadvantages, and 3 top languages that are considered pure OOP:&#xA;OOP Principles Object-oriented programming (OOP) is a programming paradigm that focuses on creating objects, which are self-contained entities that combine data (attributes) and behavior (methods). OOP principles are:&#xA;Encapsulation: Bundling data and methods together within an object, protecting internal data from unauthorized access. Inheritance: Creating new classes (subclasses) based on existing classes (superclasses), inheriting their attributes and methods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functions</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/basics/functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/basics/functions/</guid>
      <description>A function is a self-contained block of code that performs a specific task. It&amp;rsquo;s designed to be reusable and can be called from different parts of the program.&#xA;Evolution of Functions Functions have evolved in modern programming languages like Julia.&#xA;First-Class Functions: Functions are treated as values, meaning they can be: Assigned to variables Passed as arguments to other functions Returned from functions Higher-Order Functions: Functions that operate on other functions, enabling: Mapping (applying a function to each element of a collection) Filtering (selecting elements based on a condition) Reducing (combining elements using a function) Closures: Functions that capture variables from their enclosing scope, creating &amp;ldquo;stateful&amp;rdquo; functions that remember values across calls.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structures</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/basics/structures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/basics/structures/</guid>
      <description>Data structures are the way we organize and store information in memory. They are like containers that hold different types of data and provide efficient access, manipulation, and retrieval. Imagine a bookshelf: it organizes your books by genre or author, making it easier to find a specific book. Similarly, data structures organize data to be processed efficiently by algorithms.&#xA;Foundation Data structures are crucial for writing efficient and clean code. They determine how quickly you can search for data, insert new elements, or delete existing ones.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UX/UI Concepts</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/uxui/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/uxui/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Understanding UX/UI can feel overwhelming at first, but fret not! Here&amp;rsquo;s a breakdown of these closely intertwined concepts, along with a learning roadmap to kickstart your journey, from newbie to pro:&#xA;1. Decoding the Terms:&#xA;UX (User Experience): Imagine every interaction you have with a product, website, or app. The overall feeling, ease of use, and satisfaction – that&amp;rsquo;s UX. A UX Designer aims to make these interactions smooth, intuitive, and enjoyable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTML Syntax</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/html/</guid>
      <description>In this short tutorial we introduce you to HTML fundamentals. This is good enough to get you started but eventually you will need an advanced course that we provide on our home site. This is a long page so let&amp;rsquo;s get started.&#xA;What is HTML? HTML: HyperText Markup Language, aka the Blueprint for Awesome Websites&#xA;Hold your horses, HTML newbies! Before you start constructing digital masterpieces, let&amp;rsquo;s decode the mysterious acronym and uncover its true nature.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTML Forms</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/forms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/forms/</guid>
      <description>What are HTML Forms? HTML forms are interactive sections on web pages that allow users to enter and submit data. Think of them like digital versions of paper forms, where you fill in the blanks and hit &amp;ldquo;submit&amp;rdquo; to send the information along. They&amp;rsquo;re crucial for user interaction and website functionality, enabling a wide range of applications:&#xA;Gathering user information: Websites use forms for logins, contact forms, surveys, registrations, and online orders.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CSS Syntax</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/css/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/css/</guid>
      <description>Fundamentals I don&amp;rsquo;t know if you are new to CSS Or not. I will try in this page to introduce the basic concepts using AI prompts. This may be not perfect or enaugh. At the end I will invite you to our advanced course. Here&amp;rsquo;s a breakdown of CSS fundamentals:&#xA;What is CSS?&#xA;Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) is a language used to style and format the visual presentation of HTML elements on a webpage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Front End</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/front/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/front/</guid>
      <description>Fundamentals The front end is essentially the part of a website or application that you see and interact with directly. It&amp;rsquo;s like the shop window of a digital store. Here are some key things to know about the front end:&#xA;Visually appealing: Front-end developers focus on creating a user-friendly and visually appealing interface. This includes things like the layout, colors, fonts, and images. Interactive features: They also implement the interactive features that allow you to navigate the website or application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back End</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/backend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/web-design/backend/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Imagine a restaurant. When you sit down, you see the menu (front-end), the waiters taking your order (interaction), and the delicious food arriving (result). But what happens in the kitchen (back-end)? That&amp;rsquo;s where the magic happens!&#xA;Similarly, websites and apps also have two sides:&#xA;Front-End: This is what you see and interact with, like buttons, menus, and text. It&amp;rsquo;s like the restaurant&amp;rsquo;s dining area and interface. Back-End: This is the hidden part that makes everything work, like storing data, processing information, and connecting to databases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Productivity Definition</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/productivity/definition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/productivity/definition/</guid>
      <description>In software development, productivity isn&amp;rsquo;t just about cranking out lines of code as fast as possible. It&amp;rsquo;s a balance between efficiency (getting things done) and effectiveness (delivering high-quality work that meets the project&amp;rsquo;s goals). Here&amp;rsquo;s a breakdown:&#xA;What it is: Efficiency + Effectiveness: A productive developer can code well and get tasks completed quickly, but also ensure the code is clean, maintainable, and meets the project requirements. Delivering Value: Ultimately, it&amp;rsquo;s about producing software that brings value to the business or users.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategy for Productivity</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/productivity/strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/productivity/strategy/</guid>
      <description>Here are some strategies to improve developer productivity for software production:&#xA;Optimize the Development Environment:&#xA;Tool Up: Invest in the right tools. IDEs with features like code completion, refactoring, and debugging can save tons of time. Consider version control systems, code review tools, and automation for repetitive tasks. Training and Knowledge Sharing: Ensure developers are proficient with their tools and explore advanced features. Encourage knowledge sharing within the team. Streamline Workflow and Communication:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software Testing</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/productivity/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/productivity/testing/</guid>
      <description>Importance Software testing, often seen as a hurdle, actually plays a critical role in boosting productivity throughout the software development lifecycle. Here&amp;rsquo;s how:&#xA;Early Bug Detection: Testing helps uncover bugs and defects early in the development process. This is crucial because fixing bugs later in the cycle, especially after release, is significantly more expensive and time-consuming. Early detection allows for quicker fixes with minimal rework.&#xA;Reduced Rework: By catching defects early, software testing prevents developers from spending time building on top of faulty code.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
