<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>basic on Sage CS Research</title>
    <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/tags/basic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in basic on Sage CS Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sage-csr.vercel.app/tags/basic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Concepts</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/databases/concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/databases/concepts/</guid>
      <description>What are databases? Databases are the backbone of many data-centric applications. Here&amp;rsquo;s a breakdown of the fundamental concepts and lingo programmers use:&#xA;Building Blocks:&#xA;Database: An organized collection of structured data, typically stored electronically. Think of it as a digital filing cabinet for information. Table: The core unit of organization within a database. Imagine a table like a spreadsheet with rows and columns. Each table stores data about a specific subject, like &amp;ldquo;Customers&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Products.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Features</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/databases/features/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/databases/features/</guid>
      <description>Database features encompass functionalities offered by database management systems (DBMS) to manage data effectively. Here&amp;rsquo;s a breakdown of some prominent features:&#xA;Data Structuring and Manipulation:&#xA;Data Definition Language (DDL): This language allows you to create, modify, and remove the structure of a database, including tables, columns, and constraints. Data Manipulation Language (DML): This is the workhorse for interacting with data. DML commands like INSERT, UPDATE, and DELETE enable you to add, modify, and remove data within the database.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design</title>
      <link>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/databases/design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sage-csr.vercel.app/databases/design/</guid>
      <description>Database design principles are the guiding lights for creating a well-structured, efficient, and maintainable database. Here are some key principles to consider:&#xA;Data Integrity:&#xA;Minimizing Redundancy: Avoid storing the same piece of data in multiple places. This reduces errors and inconsistencies when data needs to be updated. Data Validation: Enforce rules to ensure data accuracy. For example, a &amp;ldquo;Customer Age&amp;rdquo; field might only accept values between 18 and 120. Constraints: Use database constraints like primary keys, foreign keys, and data types to restrict invalid data entry.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
